Jennifer Brana

PHD STUDENT, CARNEGIE MELLON UNIVERSITY

☑ jbrana@cs.cmu.edu | 🎖 jenniferbrana.github.io | 🖸 JenniferBrana | 🛅 jenniferbrana

Research Interests

I am interested in the intersection of hardware and software systems, particularly in the area of parallel computing and heterogeneous systems. My aim is to increase the scalability and sustainability of future computing systems.

Research areas: computer architecture; computer systems; memory systems; sustainability.

Education _

Carnegie Mellon University

Pittsburgh, PA

Ph.D in Computer Science

Beginning June 2023

Advisor: Nathan Beckmann
University of Portland

Portland, OR

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE, Cum Laude
MINOR IN COMPUTER ENGINEERING.

Aug. 2019 - May 2023

Publications_____

Kobold: Simplified Cache Coherence for Cache-Attached Accelerators

IEEE CAL 2023

Jennifer Brana, Brian C. Schwedock, Yatin A. Manerkar, Nathan Beckmann

to appear

Kobold: Simplified Cache Coherence for Cache-Attached Accelerators

WDDSA @ MICRO 2022

Jennifer Brana, Brian C. Schwedock, Yatin A. Manerkar, Nathan Beckmann

Talks and Presentations

Kobold: Simplified Cache Coherence for Cache-Attached Accelerators Kobold: Simplified Cache Coherence for Cache-Attached Accelerators

Comparison of Computer Architecture Specialization Methods for Performance and

Power Efficiency

WDDSA @ MICRO, 2 Oct. 2022 SRC @ MICRO, 3 Oct. 2022

University of Portland Founders' Day, 12 April 2022

Professional Experience _____

Carnegie Mellon University

Pittsburgh, PA

GRADUATE RESEARCH ASSISTANT

June 2023 - Present

• Researching in computer architecture.

Computer Organization Research Group (CORGI)

Carnegie Mellon University

Undergraduate Research Assistant

May 2022 - May 2023

 $\bullet \ \ {\sf Researched\ methods\ to\ design\ cache\ coherence\ protocols\ for\ cache-attached\ accelerators.}$

SENIOR CAPSTONE

Team Lift

Portland, OR; Karonga, Malawi Aug. 2022 - May 2023

• Deployed a connected network of sensors and computation nodes in an infrastructure-limited environment in Malawi, Africa.

University of Portland
Undergraduate Researcher

Portland, OR Jan. 2022 - May 2022

· Investigated CPU specialization methods to increase the performance and efficiency of Viterbi Decoding.

Simulated processor architecture using gem5 and modeled processor power consumption using McPat.

Intelligent, Complex, Adaptive, and Networks Lab

University of Portland

Undergraduate Research Assistant

May 2021 - August 2021

• Researched EEG-based view of comprehension of truth statements to understand how humans process undefined statements.

Honors & Awards

NSF Graduate Research Fellowship, GRFP NSF

CS Outstanding Student Award, For combination of coursework, research, and service. U of Portland 2023

Tau Beta Pi Induction, National engineering honor society. 2020 U of Portland

2019-2023 President's Scholarship U of Portland 2019-2023 FIRST Robotics Scholarship U of Portland

Service & Leadership _____

Tau Beta Pi University of Portland

OREGON GAMMA CHAPTER PRESIDENT

2021 - 2022

• Responsible for planning meetings and activities to engage club members ranging from career development to design competitions.

Society of Women Engineers

University of Portland

MENTOR

2020 - 2023

• Mentored freshman girls in the engineering program.

Tutoring Working Group University of Portland

STUDENT REPRESENTATIVE

· Worked with faculty members to redesign the tutoring program for the Shiley School of Engineering following the Covid-19 pandemic to increase freshman and sophomore retention rates.

Teaching

University of Portland

Theory of Computation (CS 357) Grader, Fall 2022

Digital Systems Design (EE 332) Tutor, Spring 2022

Signals & Systems (EE 262) Tutor, Spring 2022

Logic Design (EE 231) Grader and Tutor, Fall 2021 Electrical Circuits (EE 261) Tutor, Fall 2021-Spring 2022

Electrical Circuits Lab (EE 271) Lab Assistant, Spring 2021

Skills

Programming Languages C, C++, Python, Java, Assembly, MATLAB, Haskell, Verilog HDL, LaTeX **Parallel Programming** Experience in parallel/GPU computing using CUDA C/C++, OneTBB

Computer Architecture Tools Experience using gem5, SLICC, McPat, Murphi model checker, CACTI, ProtoGen/HieraGen

Proficiency with Unix, SSH, Git/Github, Xcode, VSCode. Experience in Agile